TERRANCE WILLIAMS

E: Tewilliams76@icloud.com (206) 468-4409 A: Richmond, VA http://Terrancew.com https://github.com/TerranceDWilliams1976 https://www.linkedin.com/in/tewilliams76/

| PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A creative, engaging, full stack developer with a passion for front-end development and UI Design. Specializes in customer satisfaction through teamwork and maintains a commitment to exceed expectations. Actively pursuing opportunities to provide programming skills, leadership ability, and enthusiasm to a fast-paced environment as a full stack developer.

WORK HISTORY

Woz-U - Full Stack Web Development Student

Scottsdale, AZ • 05/2018 - 11/2018

Learned how to build web applications using JavaScript and JavaScript Frameworks. Acquired skills to program using JavaScript, build database-driven web applications using popular frameworks, and create richly interactive client-side apps using the JavaScript AngularJS library. Worked 40 + hours weekly on individual and team projects.

HCA Healthcare Inc. - Practice Manager

Richmond, VA • 03/2017 - Current

- · Managed staff including physician assistants, nurses, patient coordinators and front office assistants.
- Implemented customer service evaluation protocol system, raised satisfaction rating from 63% to 80%.
- Managed timekeeping and payroll, implemented and maintained HR policies; benefit management and employee satisfaction.

United States Air Force - Military Forces Supervisor

07/1996 - 08/2016

- Directed and managed all operations for 56 employees over 6 surgical clinics.
- Managed \$300K worth of unit expenses below budget through accurate planning, waste reduction, purchasing, productivity, and cost-effective operating procedures.
- Educated team members on new technology practices and standards
- Analyzed training needs to develop new training programs or modified and improved existing programs
- Managed call center customer advocate for 5 clinics, resolved customer care complaints and issues.
- Worked with clinic managers to review training deficiencies;

SKILLS

Languages / Frameworks:

- HTML
- AngularJS
- AJAX
- Cordova
- Ionic
- NoSQL
- TypeScript
- Git
- RESTful API's
- Heroku
- Software Development
- Unit Testing
- Web Applications
- Application Design
- Bootstrap
- ¡Query
- Express
- WebAPI
- Python
- NPM
- SCRUM
- Responsive Web Design
- Information Systems
- Application Design
- SQI
- ReactJS
- Node
- Developer Tools
- http-server
- Ruby
- Ruby on Rails
- Django
- JSON
- Visual Studio Code
- Flexbox
- DOM
- Regex
- · Web Security
- Deployment
- Information Systems

developed new training programs and modified existing programs to meet organization goals.

| ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Woz U Group Project-Team Name: Team One; App Name: Game Garage
- Creating app routing module, creating header, setting up model for users, making user service, creating a log page, creating login component, connecting model to database, creating angular material dependencies, creating a home page with login and registration connection.
- The Project App was created using: Java Spring, Angular, Node, SQL.

PROJECTS

Splurty Quotes Application

This application is a random quote generating app that also gives users the option to add their own quotes to the database. This application was created as a way to learn about postgresl databases in a fun interactive way.

§ Technologies used: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Postgresl.

Live Demo: https://splurty-first-app.herokuapp.com/

My To-Do List Application

This application is a fun interactive To-Do application that utilizes many technologies to include NodeJS, and AngularJS. This project was created as a fun way to keep organized on a daily basis. § Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, AngularJS, Node.

Live Demo: https://angular-todo-app.netlify.com/

Please see resume website for additional projects and demos: http://TerranceW.com

Additional Skills

- Effective Communication
- Team Work
- Leadership
- · Public Speaking

EDUCATION

Woz U

Scottsdale, AZ • 2018

Certificate In Software Development:

Computer Science

American Military University

Charles Town, WV • 2012

Master of Arts: Criminal Justice

Grantham University

Lenexa, KS • 2007

Bachelor of Science: Engineering

Management

CompTia

2017

A+: IT Certfication